You said we did not have our best last
12 months ever, which is mostly my
fault, but we are about to have our best
12 months. What did you mean by that?
>> Best 12 months yet.
>> I think we clearly had some missteps as
a company, which will happen
periodically. I mean, part of trying to
make a portfolio of bets is that
sometimes more of them work and
sometimes less of them work. Um but I
think both in terms of product direction
and specifically on pre-training in
research we fell behind where we wanted
to be. I think we are now executing not
only the best we have ever executed but
the best of uh kind of any company in
the space and it is very fun to like the
you know the upswing is more fun after
the downswing. Uh so just looking at the
pace of models that we really have come
in the way the company has come together
and focused and made a bunch of hard
decisions in very different parts of the
company but done sort of in unison and
in one direction uh it feels it feels
great right now
>> and I want to get to all that but to
dwell on this for a second because the
last year a lot has happened. Um were
there specific decisions you can look
back on that you made that cost the
company momentum? I mean you mentioned
pre-training. I know you've always been
very close to the research team. Uh but
can you elaborate on that?
>> I I think we were trying to do too much
on the product side. Uh and so there was
like you know we and these were all
things that were actually very good
things to do. They were just not as good
as the most important thing to do which
was sort of push on the general
capability of of the intelligence. Uh so
we were doing things like a browser and
Sora and we now have a very relentless
focus on being this intelligent service
to people and I think our models are
they have gotten to be the best in the
world and they will get much much better
over the coming months and people are
really doing remarkable things but that
is what we should have been focused on
and I should have been holding everybody
to this is the one thing we'll not worry
about these sort of side quests more
>> looking at the leadership changes you
had about a year ago you brought in Fiji
Simo to help run large parts of the
company. She had to step back due to her
health. And now you and Greg Brockman,
your co-founder, are effectively
splitting responsibilities, running the
company together. Is this the setup that
you envision will continue or is this
something temporary?
>> Um, I think it's going super well. I I
we will continue to bring in and promote
uh you know new new leaders but uh it
feels and I'm you know extremely sad
about Fiji hard to like fill her shoes
but it feels good and I think Greg and I
are executing well and the company is uh
you know you can like really tell when
things are moving in the right direction
and it feels like things are moving in
the right direction.
>> How do you all make decisions you and
Greg together? Like who decides what? Do
you ever have a tie you have to break?
Uh I mean we talk a lot like a lot lot
like all of the time. Uh it's not like
this is like a big company. It's not
just Greg and I. Um there's there's like
an incredibly talented set of people
managing the research program. Um
there's an incredibly talented set of
people managing the business and we all
just talk a lot and and uh at an earlier
scale I thought it was good to just sort
of try something and adapt quickly if it
works and not spend as much time really
trying to debate the decision. at our
scale. Now, I've learned that it's much
better to spend a lot of time trying to
get to the right decision and and kind
of a measure twice, cut once approach.
privacy but like the way we the
commitments we make about not training
on businesses data and about zero data
retention uh I think this is very
important and as AI becomes more and
more embedded in our lives privacy
becomes extremely important and one
thing I worry about is there are other
efforts that think differently and will
push on hey the safety risks are so big
that AI privacy can't exist. in the same
kind of way. I think that there should
be like an AI privilege law. I don't
even think the government should be able
allowed to like compel you know a
company to give them your chat history
or whatever like you know if you talk to
a doctor or a lawyer there's a concept
of privilege. You don't have that
talking to Chad GPT. I think you should.
>> In that context though that you just
described there's also a lot of limits
on what a lawyer or a doctor can do with
your data. It's not just sharing it
externally. Do you think that that kind
of oversight should extend to how you
use
>> Yeah. No, I was going to get to
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I think there should be
legal limits of what the government can
do. I also think companies should have a
lot of restrictions on data shared with
an AI and especially if you have this
thing watching your computer, listen to
your messages, talking to you, like
yeah, I I think that this is I think
there should be something people are
much more animated about than they are.
>> How before that happens, how do you at
OpenAI govern that self-govern the use
of data? you probably have some of the
most powerful profile data that's ever
been amassed on in the history of the
world.
>> We have extremely strong internal
controls about how that's used. Uh and
we make the privacy guarantees to users
that we do. Um as we get closer to
launching this device, we'll be talking
about kind of the new privacy controls
and technology we're building for a
device that's like kind of ambiently
computing. But yeah, I think we have one
of the
more personal databases ever.
>> Apple has very publicly sued you guys
for allegedly stealing trade secrets uh
and hiring their employees uh to work on
this device with Johnny and you've
responded to it. Um and you've said it's
it's meritless, but I'm wondering it do
you worry about this slowing down the
device efforts?
>> No. Look, if first of all, I'm like a
mega Apple fanboy and I was very sad
about that. Um, and from when I first
heard about it, I was like, man, this
sounds egregious. Someone must have done
something badly. And if someone, we
don't like want any company's IP, and we
certainly don't want people who are
going to take a company's IP and bring
it to us. And if you know, we did an
investigation and found that about
somebody. Uh, we would of course just
terminate them and deal with it. Um, but
we're also going to defend someone if
they didn't do something wrong. And I I
believe after we looked into this that
this was a case of someone uh not doing
something wrong. And we tried to explain
some of that and you know more of that
will play out in a process. Um given my
understanding I don't think this is
going to slow things down.
>> How are you thinking about form factors?
Do you like I've heard you say you don't
in the past. Do you like glasses? Yeah.
Glasses.
>> I don't because I find it very
uncomfortable talking to people with
like a camera and a light like a lot.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. But there's a lot of other form
factors.
>> There's a lot of great form factors. Um
I think we'll do a small handful of form
factors. There's I think there's like
something that belongs on a table. Um
there is something that belongs in your
pocket. Uh and there is something that
like belongs on your body. Uh and it'll
take us some time to launch all of those
things. But I think the big adjustment
is going to be getting used to this idea
of a proactive computer.
>> Mhm. When you're thinking about OpenAI's
roadmap and and the business, are
consumer devices
existential in a sense? Are they purely
additative? Like and the mission that
that you guys talk about um you've got a
lot of things still happening even
though you've whittleled things down as
we talked about.
>> And you're building towards super
intelligence.
I'd be curious to know how you
personally are preparing for that. Do
you have a view of what life will look
like on the other side of what you're
building?
>> I think it will look surprisingly
similar to how it looks now. You know,
people are gonna
hang out with their families and fall in
love and get into fights and do their
hobbies and, you know, be entertained
and have a very human experience and
try, you know, get stressed and get
anxious and create value for each other
and play all kinds of strange games and
um care about other people a lot. I I
hope it'll not be that different. I hope
it'll be uh you know, the human
experience is richer. people have more
autonomy, more freedom, more wealth, can
do more um can be healthier, can kind of
have like more power to collectively
define the future and the world gets
better faster, but that the human
experience stays like a very human thing
>> if you look out over the next 12 months,
what is the biggest risk for open AI?
>> I think it's like getting safety,
alignment, and security wrong. I mean I
think it's possible that 12 months from
now we have extremely capable models and
if we are able to navigate the
transition to super intelligence in a
world where we have figured out how to
empower people,
how to make sure power is not too
concentrated, how to
deliver safety across the entire
spectrum. um how to let people feel very
in control of improving their own lives
in the future. Um that would be like a